so I don't forget.
And I always open with this.
Today is February 9th, 2026, and my name is Caitlin Sheets.
I'm here with Ayo.
We're conducting an interview in Evans Annex on the campus of Texas A&M University in College Station.
This interview is part of an oral history project documenting the experiences of Aggies for the 150th celebration of Texas A&M.
And do I have your consent to record?
Just in case paperwork gets lost.
Awesome.
Thank you for joining me, and thank you for sharing your story with me.
Can you get a little bit of the dreaded question of like, tell me a little bit about yourself, like where you were born, your name to your parents.
Yeah, yeah.
So I was born on February 26, 2004.
So like 26th birthday.
Congratulations.
I was born in Atlanta, Georgia.
from Nigeria.
They immigrated here.
My dad in 97.
My mom, I believe, like 2003 or at that time.
Yeah, so I grew up most of my life in Atlanta up until the eighth grade.
My dad, he got a job at a Georgia Bush airport where he still works at the CSA.
And so he'd been working here maybe one or two years before, by the eighth grade, when we decided we were all going to move to Texas.
Ever since then, I've been living in Humble, around the Houston area, and so I've been living here ever since.
Awesome.
That's awesome.
What made the family look from Georgia to Texas A&M, or Texas in general?
So, it was mostly, like I said, my dad.
My dad, he hadn't been working for a while up until then, just through the recession.
And so, there was opportunity in the biggest sense of work.
Like I said, he'd been working there for one or two years.
And so, we decided to just start a new life.
Yeah, that's awesome.
I also forgot that that definitely is in the smack dab middle of recession time when that's rough.
So...
When you, what high school did you go to?
I went to Humboldt High School.
Humboldt High School, awesome.
So when you were in high school and you were looking at different universities, did you look at any other universities?
In principle, you always look into stuff like U of A, UCL, and that type of stuff.
But for most part, most of my high school experience, let's say Aiden, it was always the top of my choice.
Oh, awesome.
Yeah.
what kind of your thoughts of this university before that what was like enticing about it like uh basically the court um i was in jrpc in high school and so i was already exposed into that like military kind of issue environment um and you know i'm also a big history book i always have been so kind of i saw you know it was kind of like that kind of
pool of history that not other universities necessarily raised or have and so it always kind of appeared to me in terms of like you know people always see it as like weird and it's only from my perspective it's intriguing right yeah absolutely just for my curiosity what's your what's your like you said you're interested in history what's your interest in uh so
Soviet history, like the Eastern Bloc countries as well.
Over time, I grew out into more stuff like even my parents from Nigeria, African history as well.
I'm a history buff, but in principle, Soviet Eastern Bloc, kind of military history as well.
Yeah, absolutely.
That's awesome.
And I didn't ask this before, but what's your major?
I'm a Poles major.
Oh, okay.
Awesome.
That's awesome.
Um, so what is also, are you, did you say you're a senior?
Yeah.
Congratulations.
I know that that has to feel really good.
Did you already get your senior boots and everything like that?
Yeah.
Tell me about that experience.
Um, so it was pretty cool, cool experience.
Um, just getting my senior boots, um,
Leo at Hall, he's one of the boot makers and so I helped him make a website for one of his businesses and so I had a blessing of him being able to pay for my boots which is pretty cool because you know those things aren't cheap at all.
No they aren't.
Those things aren't cheap at all and so but just the experience of wearing boots it just it feels like a culmination moment you know you always heard those clanking noises in the hallway and you know across the quad across the university but now being able to be kind of due to clanking
It's a pretty cool feeling.
It makes you feel powerful.
You stand up taller when you're in your boots.
It's definitely been a great experience.
Yeah.
So I've only been here like six months, like in Texas in general, six months.
So the culture has been very new to me.
What things, from when you moved from Georgia to here, were some things that surprised you about the culture?
I'd say, I mean, Georgia is a small state, well, relatively small in terms of, like, the amount of major cities it has.
Atlanta's really the only one.
And so kind of like just being able to see, like, different parts of the state.
You know, Houston is one thing, then there's San Antonio, then there's Dallas, then there's also a linear different things.
I'd say there's also, like, a more welcoming, like, friendly culture.
I mean, even here with, like, Howdy.
But just, you know, that kind of
It's just pretty much across the state, I'd say.
I think that's pretty cool.
And kind of going back to what I said about the state, you know, everything's bigger in Texas.
It's not really cliche.
And so, just like, it feels like a really more open, like, bigger world.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
I would also have to agree with that.
It is mind-boggling just how large it is.
Like, you see it on maps, but then to actually experience is a whole other thing.
So...
I'm assuming you live on campus at your core, right?
Do you remember those first few weeks?
What were your feelings?
What were you going through?
It was kind of like a really, like, I remember coming on campus.
I'd come on campus a couple times before, but just for FOW, for that orientation week.
I remember when we were driving up near the van field.
The van, they were doing the drills because they came a week earlier.
And they had a legendary kind of drum beat.
And my brother started laughing at me.
I was like, oh, that's you.
That's you.
So it was kind of a cool kind of, but it was kind of a cool in general kind of feeling just being here, being something I looked forward to for like four years in high school, and now I'm really doing it.
Yeah.
Um, so you said you were in ROTC.
Um, how were you introduced to that?
Uh, in high school?
Yeah, in high school.
Yeah, yeah.
Um, so it's crazy.
So the way it works is, um, the way, so everyone has, like, PE credits, obviously, that they have to do.
And so I was originally in PE.
And so, but you can take ROTC as kind of a substitute for that.
And so they usually come around me the first week of school just to see if anyone's interested.
And I figured, because I always found PE to kind of be kind of boring.
You know, they were really like the craziest athlete I got on my phone.
And so I was like, at least I can save like battery power.
Right, yeah.
But you need moreover to
a history, military history book, so it wasn't really, it was kind of a no-brainer for me, too.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
So you've always been kind of interested in military.
Is that something that runs in the family?
No.
Not at all?
First.
I guess, I mean, the closest thing, Nigeria, they had, they had, like, not a giraffe, but kind of a youth service corps, and so my mom was in that, but that's pretty much it.
That's really cool, though.
Yeah.
With your major, what is your hopeful job that you want to get?
So I want to go into cybersecurity.
On the Southern Military side, I plan on going into the Coast Guard Reserves.
So more or less my career hasn't changed, but it's more, I guess now it's more really focusing on cybersecurity.
Yeah.
More so kind of like policy aspects as well.
Right.
Yeah, that makes sense.
And that whole world to me is so confusing.
who have been writing programs and stuff like that and they try to explain it to me.
I'm just like, just like, oh.
So you have to have a really great mind and that just speaks a lot about you though.
Yeah.
So you said cybersecurity and you wanted to go to... Coast Guard.
Thank you, Coast Guard.
Have you been down to Galveston and experienced that?
I've been down to Galveston, you know, just go sometimes.
I've never been to the kind of Coast Guard base down there.
Right, okay, yeah.
I've been talking to some people down there, too, about doing interviews and stuff, and I've been trying to get people's input of, like, oh, when I'm down there, what should I go to?
What should I hit up first?
Yeah.
Um, but it's interesting to me that, um, like all of, all of, everything kind of wraps back to that, that love of history to you.
Um, what first got you interested in history?
Um, I'll be honest, I, I, I think it just started like earlier, early on, um, you know,
we started talking about World War II, and all that's, like, act as power, and all that type of stuff.
And I think it just sparked kind of, like, some important interest.
Also, around that time, I think I started watching more, like, world news as close to current events.
Yeah.
You know, my mom used to make a joke, like, when I'd get
So I think all that type of stuff, how current events, like warfares and history, you know, that was appealed to me.
Yeah, very much so.
Yeah.
So, sorry, I have problems trying to like verbalize, but how do you, because a lot of history is like really sad.
How do you, how do you deal with some of those really like emotional or sadder topics going through?
Oh, yeah.
I think, I mean, it's weird because I don't really kind of interpret it through that way.
Obviously not history.
That's so valid.
There's a lot of history that's sad, but you don't really, because it's past, you kind of interpret
and if it is kind of like, you know, there's a lot of stuff that's, you know, Holocaust, maybe whatever, you know, you interpret the lessons from those to apply to the modern area.
That's a really good point.
Yeah.
Um, those are, those are some of the things that I like to ask, like,
I had a couple interviews with the actual history department.
And so that was also a question I asked of, like, you're studying some of these really horrific things.
How do you get through that?
And they actually mentioned that, too, that it's looking at the lessons and the kind of thing.
It's interesting to me.
So in university here, has there been any professors or lecturers that you're like, like, I want to do that.
That's the kind of thing.
Oh, there have been kind of, I'd say for the most part, no.
But I'd say there are a couple that I'd say I admire, more so outside the professional, outside the professional setting, I just admire them as people.
engaged with the university, engaged in their own professional lives, their own professional journey.
And honestly, I'd say, coming up to, now I've got to be a senior in particular, a lot of upper-level classes, I'm finding a lot more of those.
That makes sense.
You get that personal.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's really cool.
Are there...
uh do you actually have with being in the core do you have time for fun things do you have time for um like for yourself to have fun and stuff like that oh yeah okay everyone does yeah that's awesome yeah um so that very first year being in the core what what were some things that you remember that really stuck out to you um i always remembered kind of like the the the lessons that it
when I was a fish, that they kind of always try to impart on us.
I remember this one guy, he's out in the army doing finance work, but he always,
Like I said, going back to that senior class, I always remember how they conducted themselves.
I always remember, you know, once I became a senior, you know, that's how I hoped to be.
That's very true.
And have you kind of taken on that role now since you are a senior?
Yeah, I mean, I hope I've done a good job into halfway through the year, but yeah, I'd say that
I mean, that literal role, all seniors, if you're not in the core, that kind of leadership model, that's the point of inspiration, quite a bit of the boots.
So hopefully I've been at the role.
Yeah, for sure.
So what are some of the, obviously, there's many differences, but the way you view the core when you were a freshman versus now as a senior?
It's changed quite a bit while
not changing at all, if that makes sense.
We've had four commandants for each year that I've been here.
So it's been kind of every year's a leadership change.
And then, of course, there's been transitions on the university level as well.
And so kind of the way the role, or rather how the court is perceived in the university and how the court behaves in the university has changed both, in my opinion, pretty better, as well as the worst.
Something I'd say, a lot of people talk about, especially old acts, they would be like, you know, the court changed that much.
But, you know, I mean, it's just life.
Everything changes.
Nothing good doesn't change.
So you just take...
By May, I won't be in the court, so it won't matter.
Wow.
What are your feelings on that?
On leaving the court?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, I'm ready.
You're ready?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
You get to that point, isn't it?
That's a really good way of looking at it because I know I would be horribly sad, but I'm really bad at goodbyes.
But I don't really think it's a goodbye for you guys because ags are so, something I've learned is ags are so proactive and they stay in touch with each other.
Yeah.
So seeing that, it's like, wow, the community, that has to say something about this place.
Has there been anything surprising being a senior?
whether that be school or core.
I haven't heard of it before, you know, senioritis, all that kind of stuff.
Even in the core, you know, I've had that time, I'm ready to go.
I've seen that for like the past three years.
So I'm really done like replicating like the tradition of you, if you want to think of it like that.
Yeah, absolutely.
Speaking of tradition, that's a really good segue.
Some of the longstanding traditions
Which ones that really mean something to you or stick with you?
I was always a fan of Mustard, mostly because I think it's like an incredible culminating point of view, especially being in the Corps.
But even if I wasn't in the Corps, I think I would like Mustard because it's just a beautiful way to honor all Aggies who have passed during the past year.
So far, the Mustard speeches have been pretty
Last year with General Downs.
So it was, you know, it's always kind of like a warm feeling to be with like people who are older than you.
It's those people who probably not, you know, aren't even thinking about college at that point.
Right.
But all gathered to honor, you know, people in our community.
Truly.
I've never heard of any other university that does these types of traditions, and still, 100 years later, they're still doing it.
Does that mean anything?
I know that's a silly question, but does that actually mean anything to you and your friends?
Oh, yeah.
I mean, the longevity of it is definitely, you know, it's great.
It's to know that, one, that it has been happening for 100 years, but also, like,
you know, more or less, as long as the university is alive and well, you know, it will happen for a hundred more.
And that, by the time I leave, you know, I leave this world, you know, I'll have a muster, I'll have a muster for friends.
You know, it's definitely beautiful.
That's a very good point.
Some things you don't like to think about death, but hey, it's kind of,
Not relaxing, but nice to know that you're going to be continued on.
Your legacy is going to be continued on kind of thing.
And so you and your friends, your friend group right now, do you guys have any plans for after you graduate and you have that little bit of time?
I don't know if you do have that time.
Do you guys have anything planned or...
like in terms of like just like just anything like uh like i don't know if you guys are taking a trip or a party or that kind of thing one of my buddies in the court he's gonna get married this summer and so i'm gonna definitely be on on the agenda for sure yeah that's exciting um
So, with the core, what are some things, because I try not to ask people, because you said there's some good and bad changes.
I'll stick to the good changes.
What are some of the good changes that you've seen?
Yeah, I'd say the core is definitely more visible on campus than it probably was my freshman year.
Discipline has probably been more set in stone.
There's, I think, going back to that first point, I think we're trying to
whether it be through football or anything else, I think we're definitely a more visible part of campus than probably we were in my freshman year.
That makes sense.
And you mentioned every four years that it's been changing, the Commandant has been changing.
With that, what are the kind of feelings,
Is there feelings of like instability or is there feelings of?
Not instability per se.
I just say, you know, like again, like rapid change, you know, everyone that comes in, they have their own agenda.
And so kind of just adapting to that.
Right.
Very fair.
What are some traditions in the core that you think you'll continue on in your life?
Or it doesn't even have to be a tradition.
It could just be habits or anything like that.
I'd say just like good time management.
Good time management.
I think for a lot of people that's the main thing they'll take from the core.
Because you do have to, you know, like I said way early on in an interview, you know,
You can have fun, but part of the sacrifice is that you have to have good time management in order to make room for that fun.
both in a civilian sector and in the military.
For sure.
And with the field that you're going into with cybersecurity, you said you want to work with the military, obviously, but do you have like a dream position or a dream job?
So, yeah, I want to serve as a cyber officer.
So still trying to figure out what that necessarily means.
But mostly kind of cyber intelligence.
For sure.
um i feel like that field is booming so um so with the okay your thoughts on um the core and would you have ever considered not joining okay this is this is kind of silly but would you ever consider not joining before or was that like always you mean like before before oh yeah so i think maybe it was like
between my junior and senior year when I was like, now you have to really make a choice.
I was like, because I think I always did sit on doing ROTC.
I did ROTC in high school.
I was like, do I really want to join the Corps?
But eventually I just came around to accept to get it.
This will be cool.
This is something that everyone's done.
I think it's just those type of, you join new organization, new institution type anxieties.
They may be there for like five minutes, but then it is
Yeah, that makes sense.
Yeah.
And segueing a little bit more.
So what, how has the core impacted your experience overall in college?
Just whether that be class or just the social aspect?
I mean, it is basically shaped more or less kind of,
done so for the better, it makes you, it's made me unique.
It's made me kind of stand out above the rest in a positive way.
And then, you know, it allows for a lot of like networks to be created.
I've been in, I've gotten opportunities and been in spaces I probably wouldn't be in because of my experience in the core.
So I've been definitely grateful.
I don't think I, like I said,
Right, yeah.
Talk a little bit about that.
What are some experiences that kind of opened up to you because of it?
Yeah, there's been a litany of stuff.
I'm just thinking about, the reason I got connected with this interview is because last summer I participated in the Army 250 parade in Washington, D.C., one of the college that he
the people who participated in this interview.
But yeah, I got to go to Washington, D.C.
I've been there before, a couple of times before, but I never like at this level for a world audience in front of the commander in chief.
So, you know, stuff like that is a pretty cool experience.
You get to be around, you know, like the networking aspect, being around people from the Citadel, VMI, other universities, West Point, being around the big army.
So it was a pretty cool experience.
Yeah.
um so i could that completely blew my mind that that you were in that direction that um what were some of the feelings and some of the the things that you saw that really are going to stick with you for life for the for the uh the parade that you did um honestly like just like the march down to when we did when we you know do
all these politicians in like tv for so long you forget to actually people real people people and so like when we we were approaching the reviewing stand you know he's he begins to stand up yeah this is for you this is real and you know so it's bad that i'll never forget that that was pretty cool that's really cool yeah
Um, uh, I found a, you guys, somebody sent me a picture of you guys doing, doing the march and I was like, wow, that's, that's so interesting.
Like, yeah, that's a part of history now.
Um, especially, was it 250th?
Yeah.
So it's like a big one.
Um, so were you,
So the preparation for that, can you walk me through a little bit about the preparation, whether that be practicing or... Yeah, so because we're in the core, we never had such extensive practice because we don't need it.
We march all the time.
Whereas perhaps other active unit units, they probably need more actual, you know, specific drill practice.
Mm-hmm.
So we got a notification a couple weeks earlier.
Usually it's ROTC, they gave ROTC, people were in Army ROTC preference, and then they, you know, opened it up for the rest of the Corps.
And so I jumped on that opportunity.
We had a bunch of, we didn't, you know, because we were all, it's over the summer, so this is June, so everyone's everywhere.
So I'll be right home.
I was in call station over the summer, you know, working and so forth.
you know, we all had to kind of like prepare ourselves, you know, in a different way.
Um, and then once we got there, um, to Washington, uh, we went to the first one to house and then we got, we had, we were lucky cause we got maybe one or two days to kind of really explore the city.
And then next day, uh, we had kind of general rehearsals.
Um, no, we didn't do the whole parade without, but just like general marching rehearsals in our blocks.
Awesome.
So when you're actually doing the marching down, what was going through your head?
I was just trying to stay locked in.
I try not to look a fool.
We marched from the area where everyone was just based all the way through the parade route.
So it was quite a while.
Sorry, how long did that...
I think the whole thing was maybe four miles.
Wow.
Three or four miles.
Um, and so it was quite a while until we got, uh, if we had a break.
Um, but yeah, we, we just marched, um, and then we, you know, just got, cause usually we, we marched with like Jody's songs and stuff, but you kind of kept it until the end.
Um, and so it was just like, please just, just stay in step.
You know, don't look a fool and you know,
But it was, it was kind of weird because, you know, there were Aggies there too.
And so they'd see us, they'd be like, you know, get in the Aggies.
You don't want to whoop, but you can't.
Right.
But that was pretty cool.
Yeah.
That's, that's something that I find interesting is I've heard a lot of stories about people recognizing other Aggies for the rings and just out in public.
Have you had those kind of moments of not even being connected to the university, but out in public, someone who recognizes you as an Aggie?
So, weird, because I don't have, I just got my ring, like, last November.
So I've had those kind of Aggie ring moments.
But definitely, like, I've seen people with, like, A&M merch just recognizing, and then sometimes we're just getting in conversation, you know,
I remember a bit of color guard.
So I've done events, you know, say the Houston Rodeo and stuff, and the organizers, you know, they're a former today, you know, they'll get to chopping it up, you know, what was it like in the core and stuff, what is your outfit?
So those things are pretty cool.
Yeah.
That's pretty cool.
That is really cool.
As you said, like the doors open kind of thing and people naturally meet, but so what are, shifting a little bit more, but what are some,
tips or things that you would tell an incoming freshman who's joining the Corps?
I'd say just kind of
like boots your shoes as well and so I went into the distribution center for the where we got our uniforms and I remember like she was the lady she was like maybe a senior cadet just working over summer I remember her I remember she was telling this other guy he was asking like advice of you like like don't take it all seriously so seriously don't take it all she still works together
coming back to it just like that's really like the only advice I give is just don't take it all too seriously I think that's important um are there any old traditions that um that you think should be brought back I'm actually not sure of all of them but any any old traditions that you wish were still around nothing comes to mind nothing okay that's fair um
I'm still also learning the history of everything.
There's a lot of different eras.
Moving on to classwork and stuff, as you said, you talked a little bit about professors that kind of stuck out to you.
Are there any that you want to emulate going forward or even that you want to get hit up and get close to now that you're graduating?
Yeah, so there are a couple of that, you know, I still kind of keep in touch with, and it's not just professors, but even like TAs as well, that, you know, we have kind of similar interests and stuff.
There's just one professor who, he was very just plain, hey, if you need anything, you know, I have a bunch of connections, you know, so I think that's a pretty cool part of the Aggie Network.
That's very true.
It's nice to know that someone has your back out there.
What is your most excited for now that you're here at the end?
Just getting out.
Yeah, you're getting out.
Just getting out and actually like...
going into the new world and working.
That's so valid.
Yeah.
And as you prepare to leave here, what are your thoughts and feelings on this university?
They're incredibly warm, I'd say.
They'll be the best years of my life so far.
Yeah.
I'm so sorry.
Of course, of course.
I have some legacy questions left over from, his name is Haskell Monroe.
He's a historian.
He also still works here.
He's been working here for years and years.
So the legacy questions I have is, say someone gave you a million dollars, but you had to put it to some part of this university.
What would it go to?
That's a good question.
All of it would have to go to some part.
Just some part.
You can divide it or whatever.
I'd say, I'd say probably Heldon Phillips.
I'd say Heldon Phillips.
That's a pretty, that's a pretty interesting building.
Yeah.
It's kind of rough.
It's rough.
It's rough, yeah.
I, yeah, could use a Facebook again.
That's fair.
Yeah.
It's very fair.
And something that I like to ask as well is what, what makes an Aggie to you?
Like, from any other
from any other person in the core, like what specifically makes an Aggie?
I don't think it necessarily is about like what makes an Aggie, but I think it's about kind of what an Aggie subscribes to, which is the core values.
So I think in that sense, kind of subscription to the core values makes you an Aggie, albeit
It could be an idea.
But I think, yeah, I think there's nothing specific to A&M that I think necessarily is worth saying, oh, yeah, this makes me an idea.
But I think it's definitely the larger, high level, the more broader core values and disciplined adherence to them that really stand out in terms of what this university produces.
Yeah, for sure.
Yeah.
That was something I very quickly learned is the core values and that it's not just talk, it's people around here actually do it.
They walk the walk.
That's super impressive to me.
And another one is, as I said, the feelings that you have in your heart for this university, if you could express that, what would that be?
Um...
I'd say any of them is an institution that, in a world of chaos, you know, you can always go back to it and say, you know, at least there's some, you know, I'd say, I'd say that's, that's, that's as simple as that sounds.
I think that's pretty much how I'd say, you know, in a world where, like, it feels like everything's just fucking burning down, you know, you know, there's one constant, you know, and everything is, well, it will change.
It's,
That makes sense.
And that's really nice.
I don't think that's silly, but I think that's very true.
And my last question before I ask you some, in case I missed anything, but my last question is, if you could give advice to the leaders of this university, what would that be?
I'd say...
where you came from.
I guess this is more so for the Aggies that were, but even for the non-Aggies, you know, remember where you came from.
Don't forget, my mom always used to tell me, don't forget who you are.
So, you know, just remember your roots, and I think that should be more guiding.
That will guide you to the correct path.
Awesome, yeah.
Was there any topics or things that you wanted to cover that I didn't touch on at all?
Okay, awesome.
Thank you so much for doing this, and I'm going to go ahead and pause it.